SUMIT KUMAR SHARMA

Hamilton, NZ 3216 | +64-20-4032-2434 | sumit1708@outlook.com |

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/thesumitsharma/ | Portfolio: https://cod3gazer.github.io/Portfolio/

Professional Summary

Trustworthy **Software Engineer with 5 years** of practical experience in designing, developing, maintaining, and refactoring software solutions. Self-motivated with a dedicated work ethic, consistently providing first-class results through effective code analysis and meeting stringent targets and deadlines.

Work History

Web Developer Intern

03/2024 - Current

RTFI - Hamilton, NZ

- Achieved 95% performance and SEO score by developing high-performance, SEO-optimised website
 from scratch using Next.js and TypeScript, significantly enhancing online visibility and engagement.
 Website link https://www.rtfi.co.nz/
- Implemented dynamic routing and ensured easy maintenance through Prismic Content Management System.
- Managed website hosting on a GoDaddy domain, deployed it via Vercel, and configured GoDaddy SMTP for the contact form using the Next.js API.

Senior Software Engineer

09/2021 - 02/2023

Accolite Digital - Delhi (NCR), India

- Improved API performance by 90% for Insight Software Hubble project.
- Identified over 5 threats to PreEmptive applications from internet hacking tools in a research project.
- Completed 60% of Jira tickets for Idera SQLSecure 4.0 release independently, with no turnback.
- Mentored and supported junior developers in .NET, Vue.js, and SQL Server, enhancing overall team performance.

Software Engineer 07/2018 - 09/2021

Larsen & Toubro Infotech - Pune, India

- Developed payroll processing applications using ASP.NET and MS SQL Server.
- Improved database performance through index tuning, efficient SQL queries, and using SQL Profiler to monitor and resolve performance issues and ensuring reliability.
- Created postmortem tool to merge and display processed data from multiple applications in reports and graphical formats using JavaScript, jQuery, AJAX, HTML, CSS, and ASP.NET.

Technical Skills

- Programming Languages: C#, C++, and JAVA
- Back End Technologies: .NET Core, Web APIs, ASP.NET and ASP.NET MVC
- Front End Technologies: Vue.js, React, JavaScript, HTML and CSS
- Databases: SQL Server and PostgreSQL
- Tools: JIRA, Bitbucket, Confluence, Jenkins, vSphere, TFS and TestRail

Education

Post Graduate Diploma: Applied Information Technology

07/2024

Waikato Institute of Technology - Hamilton, NZ

Bachelor of Engineering: Information Technology Vidyalankar Institute of Technology - Mumbai, India 05/2018

Projects

MediTrack Automated Testing Tool (WINTEC - College Project, 04/2024 – 05/2024)

• Tested MediTrack mobile application using Appium, Maven, and Appium Inspector, writing 20 test cases for login, registration, and adding drug screens.

MediTrack (WINTEC - College Project, 09/2023 - 11/2023)

• Android development for a drug management mobile application using Android Studio, Kotlin, and Firebase, streamlining drug disposal tracking and administration for a medical clinic.

Hubble - InsightSoftware (Accolite Digital, 01/2022 - 02/2023)

 Development of a web application using Agile methodology for reporting and analytics using PostgreSQL, .NET, C#, Web API, and Vue.js.

SQL Secure 4.0 - IDERA (Accolite Digital, 09/2021 - 12/2021)

 Added new features in SQL Secure 4.0 Windows application using C#, WinForms, and .NET and improved the data processing with SQL Server job management.

Web Apps for North American OTIS Elevators (L&T Infotech, 07/2018 - 09/2021)

• Development and maintenance of multiple web-based applications which handle timesheet and payroll processing of field mechanics and approval process from their supervisors.

Weekly patching automation tool (L&T Infotech, 12/2019 - 09/2020)

 Reduced weekly resource cost by 10 hours by developing an automation tool using Selenium and TestNG for weekly post-patching activities, including testing multiple applications and database connectivity.

Personal Skills

Team Management

 As a Senior Software Engineer at Accolite Digital and L&T Infotech, I have mentored and supported junior developers in a dynamic and delivery-focused environment.

Client/Customer Interaction and Communication

• Attended meetings with stakeholders to understand upcoming tasks, provide insights, and demonstrate excellent verbal and communication skills.

A team leader and a team player

 As a full-stack developer at Accolite Digital, I led the backend team and actively contributed to the frontend team, showcasing my ability to be both a leader and a collaborative team member.

Willingness to learn

 Over the past five years, I have continuously learned new skills and technologies with a positive problem-solving attitude, adapting to a dynamic and evolving work environment.

Decision-making and time management

• Demonstrated strong decision-making and time management skills as the leader of the project's backend team, efficiently analyzing and fixing technical issues to ensure timely delivery.

Certifications & Accomplishments

- Received the "Pat on the Back" Award for outstanding performance, service, and dedication in the months of November 2021 and June 2020.
- Udemy Complete Angular Course: Beginner to Advanced Certificate Link (01/2021 04/2021)

Hobbies And Interests

Sketching, Video Gaming, Table Tennis, and graphic designing

References

Reference available upon request.